

# MOHIT Kanwar

Principal consultant Financial Technologies

#### **CONTACT**

PHONE NUMBER: +91 858-883-2476 https://mohitkanwar.com mmkanwar@gmail.com

#### **KEY HIGHLIGHTS**

- Innovation and transformation in Fintech Industry – National University of Singapore
- SAFE 5.2 certified
- Certified Scrum Product Owner
- Team Kanban Practitioner
- Certified Scrum Master
- Backbase Certified Solution Architect
- Backbase Certified
  Backend developer
- Backbase Certified
  Frontend Developer

### Summary

Experienced Banking Software Consultant with a demonstrated history of working in the financial information technology and software management industry. Skilled in different frameworks of Java, JavaScript, and other upcoming technologies.

Worked with world-class banking products like FEBA (Finacle), Backbase, Liferay etc.

Strong consulting professional with Executive education on Fintech Innovations and transformations in financial services from the National University of Singapore, MBA focused on Information Technology from ICFAI, and a B. Technology from Punjab Technical University.

### **Work Experience & Credentials**

# Xebia IT Architects – Center of Excellence management 2019- Present

Leading Xebia's center of excellence for BFSI and partnership, I was able to grow the head count and project counts to multi-fold. I was able to increase the strategic partnerships from 1 to 5+. Part of my roles include team management, solutions architecture design, application of design thinking to innovate accelerators and tools to improve productivity. Handled projects based on Backbase, i-exceed, Mambu, idmission, Actico and green field development.

I am also managing Xebia's Knowledge Exchange program for internal and external training management programs. It includes blogging, tech-talks and other knowledge sharing platforms.

# Clix Capital – Loan Origination and Onboarding System 2019-2019

I delivered a multi-channel loan origination and customer onboarding system by defining the technical requirements, interacting with the tech vendors. With this project, we were able to reduce loan disbursement time from a few days to a few minutes.

This project served multiple loans including personal, device financing and other loans. The green field project was developed using Angular and Java (Spring-Boot).

# Xebia IT Architects – Backbase, Liferay 2014- 2019

As a Sr. Consultant, I worked with multiple banks and banking products to strategize and develop banking solutions for different customers. The roles include development, designing of internet and mobile banking systems, coaching and mentoring tech teams on different products including Backbase and Liferay. I was responsible for omni-channel delivery for different banks, including support and maintenance of the IT systems. Java, Python, JavaScript, AngularJs, Spring, SpringBoot, Jenkins, TDD, Junit,

#### **KEY EXPERIENCES**

- COE LEAD
- TECHNO-FUNCTIONAL CONSULTANT
- SOLUTION ARCHITECT
- PRODUCT OWNER
- SCRUM MASTER
- PRE-SALES ENGINEER
- COACH
- FULLSTACK DEVELOPER

### **TECHNOLOGIES**

- JAVA
  - SPRING
  - SPRINGBOOT
  - SPRING CLOUD
  - SPRING SECURITY
  - LOMBOK
  - HIBERNATE
- JAVASCRIPT
  - ANGULAR
  - REACT
  - JQUERY
- MOBILE
  - ANDROID
  - o IOS
  - REACT-NATIVE
    - PWA
- ARCHITECTURE
  - MICROSERVICE
  - MONOLITHIC
  - EVENTS BASED
  - LAYERED
- FRAMEWORKS
  - BACKBASE
  - LIFERAY
  - I-EXCEED
  - MAMBU
  - ACTICO

#### **TALKS**

- BACKBASE CONNECT
- RSG PUNE

# Sapient Nitro – Backbase Developer 2013-2014

As a Sr. Associate I was responsible to deliver customer facing financial application for a U.S. based Fintech. I was responsible for developing frontend widgets, and backend services using Backbase. Core technologies: Java, Spring, JQuery, Maven, MySQI etc.

# Infosys Ltd. – FEBA (Finacle E-Banking) 2008-2013

Designing, Developing, Customizing, Supporting and pre-sales for FEBA (Finacle E Banking Architecture) product from Infosys Ltd (Now Edgeverve). The technologies include: Java, Ant, EJB, XML, JavaScript, Oracle, MS Sql, and other in-house tools.

## Sebiz Infotech – SEO Trainee 2007-2007

Developing and managing SEO friendly websites, while increasing page rank and the marketing capabilities for customers by enhancing content, networking, and improving page performances. Technologies HTML, CSS, JavaScript, DotNet etc.

#### **Career History**



### **Education History**

National University of Singapore (2020) ICFAI (University Tripura) (2010) Punjab Technical University

(2008)

Innovation and transformation in financial technologies

MBA – IT services

B.Tech – Electronics and Communication